# Mahmoud Bayoumi Said Bayoumi

Cairo, Egypt

+201068453392 | mahmoudtotti120@gmail.com

https://github.com/MahmoudBayoumi58

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-bayoumi-686aa91a9

# **Professional Summary**

Due to 3+ years of experience as a Python Backend Developer Since 2021 Until Now; Especially, in data crawling and developing new technologies using Python frameworks (Django, Flask), i seek to be one of the Staff for achieving more success & progress together.

## **Experience**

# · Python Developer - Dar-Kasb, Saudi Arabia

August 2023 - Present

- Developed RESTful APIs.
- Optimized database queries.
- •Implemented authentication and authorization mechanisms.
- Integrated third-party services.
- •Implemented background task queue using Celery.
- •Deployed applications using Gunicorn, Nginx, and Supervisor.

## Python Developer - Z2data, United States of America

April 2022 - August 2023

- •Developed and maintained automation tools, specifically scraping tools using Python (Requests, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, Puppeteer, LXML, JSON, MongoDB, Django).
- Wrote validation schemas in MongoDB.
- Developed RESTful APIs.
- Integrated third-party services.

# Python & Robotics Instructor - shine Academy, Egypt

August 2021 - April 2022

- Taught students programming concepts using Python, enhancing their coding skills.
- •Programmed robots, guided students through the programming stage.

#### Education

# • Higher Technological Institute, 10th of Ramadan

Class 2021

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Grade Point Average: Excellent (3.64)

#### **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: Python, C++
- Databases: SQL, MongoDB, PostgresSQL, Redis, Sqlite3
- Frameworks: Django, Flask
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Angular
- Task Queue & Messaging: Celery
- Others: Web Scraping, RESTful APIs

# **Backend Development Skills**

- Develop back-end components to improve responsiveness and overall performance
- Write effective, scalable code & Integrate user-facing elements into applications
- · Assess and prioritize feature requests
- Developing applications using the python programming language.
- Involvement in all aspects of the software development life cycle, from requirements gathering to testing and deployment
- Testing applications thoroughly before deployment in order to ensure that they are free of errors
- Updating software programs as new versions become available
- Keep up to date with emerging trends and technologies in Python development.
- Debugging codes when required and troubleshooting any Python-related queries
- Developed and maintained automation tools, specifically scraping tools using Python (Requests, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, Puppeteer, LXML, JSON, MongoDB,

Django).

- Implemented background task gueue using Celery
- Deployed applications using Gunicorn, Nginx, and Supervisor.
- Wrote validation schemas in MongoDB
- Implemented authentication and authorization mechanisms.

## Certifications

- Using Python to Access Web Data, Coursera; June 2021 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/HZSVCP3N4FXQ
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), Coursera; April 2021 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/KSKDRVSUQGFH
- Python Data Structures, Coursera; April 2021 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/BNWW996BJFZP

# **Projects**

• Smart System of Skin Cancer Classification using Deep Learning

Developed a GUI application using a trained model for classifying skin lesions.

• Full Stack Real-Time Chat System using Django Channels

Developed a full-stack real-time chat system to practice and enhance skills in WebSockets.

Vote Election Booth System

Created an e-voting system to solve traditional voting issues.

Desktop App for COVID-19 Tweets

Built an app to search and retrieve tweets using Twitter APIs.

• Dynamic Crawling Engine

Created a dynamic engine for data scraping using Django.

• Smart Home Automation System

Built a home automation and security system using 1Sheeld and various sensors.

# **Courses & Trainings**

- Embedded System Diploma, Artronix Company: Cairo; From June To Septemper 2020
- Python Machine Learning Diploma, Artronix Company: Cairo; From June To August 2020
- Online Python Django Course, YouTube Channel; October 2022 https://youtube.com/@traversymedia
- Online Python Django Web Framework Course, YouTube Channel; April 2022 https://youtube.com/@freecodecamp
- Online Django Tutorial, YouTube Channel; November 2023 https://youtube.com/@abdelrahmangamal
- Online Python Back-end Web Development Course (with Django), YouTube Channel; June 2024 https://youtube.com/@freecodecamp

#### Languages

· Arabic: Native Speaker

• English: B1

#### **Personal Skills**

- Proven ability to work in diverse environments and deliver efficient results
- Coordinate with internal teams to understand user requirements and provide technical solutions
- Working closely with other members of the development team, as well as customers or clients, in order to ensure that applications are developed according to specifications
- Assisting senior developers in mentoring junior staff members
- Excellent problem solving and communication abilities, in order to be able to solve complex problems that may arise during the development process
- The ability to work independently as well as part of a team

# **Reference & Last Update**

Available under request & Last Update in July 2024